Lucy Stone Letters
Lucy Stone Letters
1852-1893
Stone, Lucy, 1818-1893.
14 items (SC)
Papers of the American feminist, abolitionist, and suffragist. Outgoing correspondence concerning speaking engagements (Emily Blackwell, Grace A. Oliver, F. B. Sanborn); articles submitted to newspapers; commitment to the abolitionist cause (Sarah Grimkè, Thomas Wentworth Higginson); and solicitation of support for women's rights (Samuel Edward Herrick, George W. Pellew).
149276
Biographical History
Lucy Stone (1818-1893) was and American feminist, abolitionist, and suffragist who founded the American Woman Suffrage Association in 1869.
1818 Born in Brookfield, Massachusetts
1847 Graduated from Oberlin College becoming the first woman in Massachusetts to earn a college degree
1848 Hired by the Garrisonian Massachusetts Anti-Slavery Society
1850 Organized the first National Woman's Rights Convention
1855 Married Henry Blackwell, but kept her maiden name
1857 Gave birth to her only child, Alice Stone Blackwell
1869 Founded the American Woman Suffrage Association
1870 Started The Woman's Journal
1890 Merged the American Woman Suffrage Association with the National Woman Suffrage Association to form the National American Woman Suffrage Association
1893 Died at her home in Dorchester, Massachusetts
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Lucy Stone Letters consist of fourteen items of outgoing correspondence, reflecting her extensive involvement with the women's rights movement. Included in the collection are speaking invitations, articles submitted to newspapers, and requests for assistance in the feminist cause.
Among the letters concerning speaking arrangements are items to Grace A. Oliver and Franklin Benjamin Sanborn inviting them to guest lecturer at various meetings, and a letter to Emily Blackwell insisting upon Stone's own need to have ample time between speaking engagements to rest and prepare adequately.
Also in the collection are three items that were submitted to newspapers as articles. One item is a postcard sent to the Daily Advertiser of Boston regarding the deadline for women to be assessed and registered as voters for the School Committee. A second item is an article submitted to the Springfield Republican regarding the Farmers' Institute's adoption of the resolution for equal political rights for women. And the third piece is an article from Lucy Stone to an unknown newspaper which has been filed under Miscellaneous. This article is a report on the meeting of the Executive Committee of the Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association.
Letters to Sarah Moore Grimkè and Thomas Wentworth Higginson suggest Lucy Stone's equal commitment to the abolitionist movement. Also, in a letter about a Miss Francis to Alice Baker, Stone writes:
"...she probably has the papers of L. Maria Child. And these were rich with the manuscripts of all of the rare saints of the old anti slavery time, when gods and goddesses, clothen with common clay, wrote letters and took up the duties of human beings towards the slave."
Lucy Stone also solicits help from various people. In a letter to Samuel Edward Herrick, Stone asked that he raise the issue of the Municipal Suffrage for Women at the next Congregational Ministers' meeting. And in a letter to George W. Pellew, she requests a meeting with reference to securing legislative passage of the bill for Municipal Suffrage for Women.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection contains one series, Correspondence, which is arranged alphabetically by recipient.
Subject and Genre Headings
Activism and social reform; Blackwell, Emily, 1826-1910.; Grimkè, Sarah Moore, 1792-1873.; Herrick, Samuel Edward, 1841-1904.; Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911.; Oliver, Grace A. (Grace Atkinson), 1844-1899.; Pellew, George W.; Sanborn, F. B. (Franklin Benjamin), 1831-1917.; Stone, Lucy, 1818-1893.; The Woman's journal.; Abolitionists -- United States.; Feminists -- United States.; Social reformers -- United States.; Suffragists -- United States.; Women's rights.; Letters (correspondence); Feminists.; Social reformers.; Suffragists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Baker, Alice, 20 Mar 1882 (Sc 41)
  - Blackwell, Emily (?), 27 Feb 1852? (Sc 41)
  - Borden, Mrs., 27 Apr 1889; undated (Sc 41)
  - Daily Advertiser, 31 Aug 1881 (Sc 41)
  - Grimkè, Sarah Moore, undated (Sc 41)
  - Herrick, Samuel Edward, 31 Jan 1893? (Sc 41)
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, undated (Sc 41)
  - Oliver, Grace Atkinson, 23 Dec 1883 (Sc 41)
  - Pellew, George W., 18 Jan 1889 (Sc 41)
  - Sanborn, Franklin Benjamin, 27 Jan 1884? (Sc 41)
  - Springfield Republican, 20 Dec 1889 (Sc 41)
  - Miscellaneous, 08 Sep 1883; undated (Sc 41)